Bathed in sunshine and surrounded by misty mountaintops.
沐浴着阳光 四周云雾缭绕的山巅环绕
It beckons silently.
它无声地召唤着
Machu Picchu.
马丘比丘
The Lost City of the Incas.
印加帝国的失落之城
lies eight thousand feet up in the Andes.
坐落于安第斯山脉八千英尺的高处
It's a magic.
它充满魔力
and traction.
令人神往
that you can feel it here.
在这里你能真切地感受到
It's known all over the world that Monte Peach is one of the magnetic centers.
蒙特皮丘（原文Monte Peach疑为Machu Picchu的误写 根据后文统一译为马丘比丘）举世闻名 是古代世界的磁力中心之一
Of the ancient world.
（古代世界的）磁力中心之一
Built more than 500 years ago.
建于500多年前
Machu Picchu'sism is still very much intact.
马丘比丘的神秘感至今依旧完好无损
In fact, the site has become Peru's most popular tourist destination.
实际上 这里已成为秘鲁最受欢迎的旅游胜地
attracting people from all over the globe.
吸引着来自世界各地的游客
Even in the rain and fog.
即便是在雨雾之中
It's an incredible feeling combing the ruins.
漫步废墟间 那种感觉难以言表
Yeah, you're just surrounded by gorgeous landscapes and uh
没错 你四周尽是绝美的风景 还有……
Amazing.
太令人惊叹了
It's it's magical.
这……这太神奇了
It's magical, you know.
你知道 这真的很神奇
I mean, you can't be in a place like this and not feel the magic.
我是说 身处这样的地方 你很难不感受到那份神奇
Forgotten for centuries.
被遗忘了几个世纪
Machu Picchu's magic was rediscovered by explorer Hiram Bingham in 1911.
1911年 探险家海勒姆·宾厄姆重新发现了马丘比丘的魔力
Over the decades,
数十年来
very few followed in Bingham's footsteps.
追随宾厄姆脚步的人寥寥无几
But today, thanks to Peru's newfound political stability,
但如今 得益于秘鲁新获得的政治稳定
all that is changing.
一切都在改变
Now hordes of visitors descend daily on Machu Picchu.
如今 每天都有大批游客涌入马丘比丘
scrambling over the terraces and through the ruins.
在梯田和废墟间穿梭
Last year alone, more than 300,
仅去年一年
000 people climbed these weathered stone steps.
就有超过30万人攀登了这些饱经风霜的石阶
A cause for concern according to some.
这引起了一些人的担忧
When you get
当你看到
Five, six hundred a day now,
现在每天有五六百人
fifteen hundred a day in the high season,
旺季时每天多达一千五百人
and you're looking at
而你正看着
you know, double or triple that when it becomes really
你知道 当它真正火起来时 人数会是现在的两三倍 呃……那会造成很大的破坏
popular, uh that's gonna do a lot of damage.
它本不该承受这些
It wasn't meant for that.
但这可能无法阻挡商业的力量
But that may not stop the forces of commerce.
许多秘鲁人希望利用这座传奇城市的巨大吸引力
Many in Peru hope to capitalize on this legendary city's mass appeal.
让它更便于游览 并提供更好的设施
making it more accessible and offering better amenities.
比如一家五星级酒店
a five star hotel, for example.
尽管环保主义者对此表示担忧
Despite the conservationist fears,
当地酒店老板何塞·科克林（Jose Keklin）
Jose Keklin, a local hotel owner,
表示 马丘比丘和秘鲁还能接待更多游客
says Machu Picchu and Peru can handle a few more tourists.
为什么不呢？呃……为什么不和世界其他地方一样呢？
why not um being like the rest of the world?
为什么不呃……
Why not uh
向世界展示我们的特色呢？
expose and show much feature to the rest of the world.
这是个如此美妙的地方 为什么要只让少数人独享呢？
It's it's such a wonderful place that why keep it to the few?
在这个极度贫困的国家
In this desperately poor country,
这种想法很普遍
Those feelings are common.
看看阿瓜斯·卡连特斯（Aguas Calientes）就知道了
Just look at Aguas Calientes.
这座小镇因游客搭乘前往山顶的巴士而兴起 完全依靠旅游业生存
The town sprang up where visitors board buses headed for the summit and exists solely on the tourist trade.
游客在此搭乘前往山顶的巴士 小镇完全依赖旅游业生存
It's a cramped jumble of stalls where the locals sell arts and crafts to foreigners.
这里是一个拥挤杂乱的摊位群 当地人在这里向外国人出售手工艺品
For the vendors.
对于商贩们来说
And for guides like Jose Correa,
对于像何塞·科雷亚（Jose Correa）这样的导游来说
Machu Picchu means Mucho de Nero.
马丘比丘意味着“很多钱”（Mucho de Nero 此处为意译 原文可能想表达类似“大把钞票”的意思 因“Nero”本身无直接对应“钱”的含义 但结合语境做此处理）
I think this is our future.
我认为这就是我们的未来
This is because they are national treasure.
这是因为它们是国宝
But at what cost to this cultural treasure?
但这座文化瑰宝要付出什么代价呢？
Most agree.
大多数人对此表示认同
Machu Picchu's mystique rests largely on its location.
马丘比丘的神秘感很大程度上源于其地理位置
remote and at one time solitary.
偏远且曾经人迹罕至
In danger now of being overwhelmed by crowds and development.
现在却面临着被人群和开发淹没的危险
It's clear there needs to be a balance.
显然 需要找到一个平衡点
It's true.
的确如此
the lost city of the Incas.
印加人的失落之城
is lost no more.
已不再失落
It has been found.
它已被发现
and the secrets out.
秘密也已泄露
The modern world is closing in on its beauty and grandeur.
现代世界正逐渐侵蚀它的美丽与壮观
Ironically, that may be its undoing.
具有讽刺意味的是 这或许正是它的末日
From Achu Picchu
从马丘比丘（原文“Achu Picchu”应为拼写错误 改为“Machu Picchu”的中文译名“马丘比丘”）来看
Time may be running out.
时间可能不多了